<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Adaptive Philosophy Blog</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/"/>
  <updated>2019-01-27T18:15:32.584Z</updated>
  <id>http://adaptivephilosophy.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Daniel DuBois</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Identity and Consciousness</title>
    <link href="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2019/01/20/identity-and-consciousness/"/>
    <id>http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2019/01/20/identity-and-consciousness/</id>
    <published>2019-01-20T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-01-27T18:15:32.584Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;
Science is often thought to give us a picture of the universe in which consciousness is somehow a byproduct of physical processes. The process of scientific discovery brought us to an underlying idea that there exists some expanding structure that holds &lt;i&gt;energy&lt;/i&gt;, unevenly dispersed and clumped in various states, that is continuously shifting toward a state of equilibrium with some mathematically predictable regularity. Perhaps through an incredible stroke of luck and or by countless tries, out of this sea of energy there evolved the formation of complex material structures called brains, which are each interacting in such a way to create little independent realities, live awareness or consciousness that holds information about change over a short interval. The information contained in these moments of awareness is updated continuously, streaming together to create the experience of an agent moving through time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If only given a physical explanation for the rise of consciousness, it seems to follow that the identity of the experiencing agent, represented by some structure of neurons firing in some way, could arise from more than one particular brain over the lifetime of the universe. Consider two brains that were physically identical in every way or copies. Swapping out the particular neurons for the ones in the other copy brain would not seem to change it.  It is interesting that the brain is changed significantly over time, with aging or through brain damage, and even moment to moment as we are reading, yet we seem to shift into these different brains and continue on, even though we have different brain configurations. Consider a brain that morphed into one that was exactly like your brain or if we were to recreate another brain like yours after you die, or even somehow brought your same brain back online after you died.  Would you come back to life?  The experience differs from moment to moment depending on the particular brain state, the experiencing agent remains somewhat continuous. People can also continue on in some way without their memories, as can happen with Alzheimer&#39;s disease.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Consider also that the universe may exist as a static space-time block, with the past, present, and future states within it, possibly containing multiple paths or multiple overall states for each moment.  It would seem that if there is a continuous experiencing agent that is just physical processes in the brain, the physical processes could be re-created in another brain and could exist in many brains. It could be the case then, that after death the experiencing agent continues somewhere else where an identical process is unfolding anywhere in time. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It could be that every stream of consciousness is the really the same Agent moving along the different streams, one at a time like movies. It is possible that you could die any day and wake up living the life of any other person in time. You could die and live this life over and over, each time forgetting and living it the same way. You could live out multiple variations of this life. Perhaps all life forms that are conscious are actually You moving along another timeline as someone or something else, forgetting on a conscious level all about what it is like to live the other lives, like when you wake up from a dream and quickly forget it. Death would not even be necessary for it to happen. If your memories are limited to the structure of your brain, you could forget you were doing it and pick up where you left off in each particular brain. You could be doing it every day.  Given that possibility, perhaps consider with greater care how you treat other people and other living beings. You might have to go through those lives some other time through this world and you can die at any moment, and will die fairly soon regardless.
&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Philosophy" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/categories/Philosophy/"/>
    
    
      <category term="philosphy" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/philosphy/"/>
    
      <category term="identity" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/identity/"/>
    
      <category term="time" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/time/"/>
    
      <category term="spacetime" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/spacetime/"/>
    
      <category term="death" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/death/"/>
    
      <category term="consciousness" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/consciousness/"/>
    
      <category term="conjecture" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/conjecture/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Identity, Consciousness, and Time References</title>
    <link href="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2018/12/05/identity-and-time-references/"/>
    <id>http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2018/12/05/identity-and-time-references/</id>
    <published>2018-12-05T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-01-27T18:11:55.456Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        
        
          

&lt;p&gt;
This is a link to an article in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/identity-time/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;
        
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Links" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/categories/Links/"/>
    
    
      <category term="identity" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/identity/"/>
    
      <category term="time" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/time/"/>
    
      <category term="links" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/links/"/>
    
      <category term="philosophy-links" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/philosophy-links/"/>
    
      <category term="time-identity" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/time-identity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Majestic Unfolding Nature</title>
    <link href="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2018/12/05/nature-unfolding/"/>
    <id>http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2018/12/05/nature-unfolding/</id>
    <published>2018-12-05T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-12-09T04:56:48.041Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        
        
          





&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-sec-1&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;Bugs video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I
        
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Links" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/categories/Links/"/>
    
    
      <category term="links" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/links/"/>
    
      <category term="home-links" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/home-links/"/>
    
      <category term="animal-video" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/animal-video/"/>
    
      <category term="nature" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/nature/"/>
    
      <category term="adaptation" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/adaptation/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Moments with the Stars</title>
    <link href="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2016/07/13/moments-with-the-stars/"/>
    <id>http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2016/07/13/moments-with-the-stars/</id>
    <published>2016-07-13T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-01-27T17:17:56.772Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;
I&#39;m sitting by myself on a deck at a cabin in Northern Arizona. A few moments ago I was reading about spirals on my phone after looking at some pictures possibly created by the debris of smashed atomic partials. It is about 20 to 25 minutes past midnight Wednesday, July 13th, 2016. I am far away from any nearby city with lights and the moon isn&#39;t out yet, so I can see stars very bright and clear twinkling slowly in the blackness of outer space above me. There are bats fluttering around in the night chasing bugs. The wind is blowing gently in the pine trees and on my skin. It is chilly and I shiver a little when a moist breeze blows lightly by my skin, giving me a small flush of goosebumps then fading away. Little insects are tapping the screen behind me and there is a steady rhythm of crickets chirping all around me out in the forest.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I look up again at just the right time to see a good shooting star appear quickly then fade out silently across the sky. I usually make a good wish when I see one. The powerball is up high again&amp;#x2026; Maybe that one again I say to myself.. But I hesitate. After considering a few.. I&#39;m really not sure&amp;#x2026; What should I really wish for this time?&amp;#x2026; I almost died a few weeks ago and I am recovering from a major abdominal surgery.  I came back from the dead and now I&#39;m out here in the forest at night far away from everyone.  And now I just let that wish sit, thinking there must be some other wish more meaningful to make here. The whole thing is so beautiful that I&#39;m suddenly overwhelmed with gratitude.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is a soft immediate slowly building response in my body awareness field that feels breathtaking. It is a bit like the chills or goosebumps, but more delicate and internal, as if a Higher Consciousness in the Universe was listening to my thoughts and let me feel a loving presence. It is that gentle tingly feeling in my body awareness.  It seems mysterious and spiritual.  It must be what they call Qi or perhaps a &quot;Holy Ghost.&quot; I&#39;m not sure. I have felt it before.  It does appear every so often when I&#39;m moved or ponder about certain things in times like these. It seems to like and respond to different thoughts and observations. It is very pleasant.  
&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Spiritual Moments" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/categories/Spiritual-Moments/"/>
    
    
      <category term="spirituality" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/spirituality/"/>
    
      <category term="moments" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/moments/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Welcome to the Blog</title>
    <link href="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2016/06/15/welcome-post/"/>
    <id>http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2016/06/15/welcome-post/</id>
    <published>2016-06-15T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-12-09T04:30:22.085Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-sec-1&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;Thanks For Visiting My New Website!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&#39;ve been playing around with the blog idea for while, setting it up, and testing different generators and editors. I finally settled on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt; blog with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iissnan/hexo-theme-next&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Next theme&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; for my editor. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nuance.com/for-individuals/by-product/dragon-for-mac/software/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Dragon Dictate&lt;/a&gt; software seems to have difficulty with selecting and editing the text in Emacs, so I also use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Sublime text editor&lt;/a&gt; for dictating text. I write the post in &lt;a href=&quot;http://orgmode.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Org mode&lt;/a&gt;, which the generator renders as HTML when I export it into hexo. So far I am happy with it. I had a little difficulty getting citations to export into HTML correctly, which led me on a small excursion, but I think I can just edit the HTML to have the correct in-text citations for now.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Now for the writing! For this blog, I plan to write about my experiences providing philosophical counseling and helping people with trance/hypnosis/spirituality/meditation over the past few years. I also plan to write about topics that I&#39;m currently researching or reflecting on – usually things related to philosophy, psychology, politics, culture, personal experiences and other interests. I may repost some of my old articles and papers. When I finish reading an article or a book, I may post a short review or some reflections about it. This will be a casual blog with open discussion about anything. If you have any ideas for things you would like to see discussed, please feel free to post the ideas and questions in the comment sections.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The style for the comments is Internet casual conversational; however, please be polite and constructive when discussing topics with others.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Thanks for checking it out. I hope you find something to enjoy. I&#39;ll probably keep tweaking the website for a while, but I hope to have a new post every month or so.  You can check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://adaptivephilosophy.io/about/&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; section for short bio of my adult career and education.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cash.me/$adaptivephilosophy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Much Love! Thank you for your support and encouragement! $&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Blog" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/categories/Blog/"/>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="editors" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/editors/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
