<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Adaptive Philosophy Blog</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-10T02:48:11.913Z</updated>
  <id>http://adaptivephilosophy.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Daniel DuBois</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Identity and Time References</title>
    <link href="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2018/12/05/identity-and-time-references/"/>
    <id>http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2018/12/05/identity-and-time-references/</id>
    <published>2018-12-05T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-12-10T02:48:11.913Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
 
        
        
          
<p>
This is a link to an article in the <a href="https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/identity-time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy</a> called <a href="https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/identity-time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Identity Over Time</a>.  It is some background reference for some things I want to write about. I plan to update this with some more links.
</p>

<a href="https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/identity-time/" target="_blank"><img src="/links/website-previews/sep-identity-time-link.PNG" align="center" width="650" height="400" alt="Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy - Identity Over Time" title="Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy - Identity Over Time"/></a>
       
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Links" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/categories/Links/"/>
    
    
      <category term="links" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/links/"/>
    
      <category term="philosophy-links" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/philosophy-links/"/>
    
      <category term="identity" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/identity/"/>
    
      <category term="time" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/time/"/>
    
      <category term="time-identity" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/time-identity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Majestic Unfolding Nature</title>
    <link href="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2018/12/05/nature-unfolding/"/>
    <id>http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2018/12/05/nature-unfolding/</id>
    <published>2018-12-05T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-12-09T04:56:48.041Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        
        
          





&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-sec-1&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;Bugs video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
<p>
I decided I would start posting some nature and animal videos that I like to start the blog.  I've been busy the past few years and have not had the time I had hoped to write blog posts.  Witnessing the miracle of evolution and creation reminds me to take a step back and wonder about it.  With this blog, I want to appreciate and notice how things can slowly adapt to changing environments and situations and can evolve in perfectly marvelous ways to fill their little spaces and roles in the ecosystem.  Every day I see stuff all around me that seems magical and wondrous like this and it defies belief. I intend to draw attention to our ability to adapt and evolve in various ways every day in little ways as individuals and as a species. Each of us is doing some little wiggle in some larger system, the Geist of our world and times, and it includes every conscious living thing doing their thing. So I'll will just wiggle and waggle here a little bit.
</p>
        
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Links" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/categories/Links/"/>
    
    
      <category term="links" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/links/"/>
    
      <category term="home-links" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/home-links/"/>
    
      <category term="animal-video" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/animal-video/"/>
    
      <category term="nature" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/nature/"/>
    
      <category term="adaptation" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/adaptation/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Moments with the Stars</title>
    <link href="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2016/07/13/moments-with-the-stars/"/>
    <id>http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2016/07/13/moments-with-the-stars/</id>
    <published>2016-07-13T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-12-09T04:25:40.557Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;
I&#39;m sitting by myself on a deck at a cabin in Northern Arizona. A few moments ago I was reading about spirals on my phone after looking at some pictures possibly created by the debris of smashed atomic partials. It is about 20 to 25 minutes past midnight Wednesday, July 13th, 2016. I am far away from any nearby city with lights and the moon isn&#39;t out yet, so I can see stars very bright and clear twinkling slowly in the blackness of outer space above me. There are bats fluttering around in the night chasing bugs. The wind is blowing gently in the pine trees and on my skin. It is chilly and I shiver a little when a moist breeze blows lightly by my skin, giving me a small flush of goosebumps then fading away. Little insects are tapping the screen behind me and there is a steady rhythm of crickets chirping all around me out in the forest.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I look up again at just the right time to see a good shooting star appear quickly then fade out silently across the sky. I usually make a good wish when I see one. The powerball is up high again&amp;#x2026; Maybe that one again I say to myself.. But I hesitate. After considering a few.. I&#39;m really not sure&amp;#x2026; What should I really wish for this time?&amp;#x2026; I almost died a few weeks ago and I am recovering from an major surgery.  I came back from the dead and now I&#39;m out here in the forest at night far away from everyone.  And now I just let that wish sit, thinking there must be some other wish more meaningful to make here. The whole thing is so beautiful that I&#39;m suddenly overwhelmed with gratitude.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is a soft immediate slowly building response in my body awareness field that feels breathtaking. It is a bit like the chills or goosebumps, but more delicate and internal, as if a Higher Consciousness in the Universe was listening to my thoughts and let me feel a loving presence. It is that gentle tingly feeling in my body awareness.  It seems mysterious and spiritual.  It must be what they call Qi or perhaps a &quot;Holy Ghost.&quot; I&#39;m not sure. I have felt it before.  It does appear every so often when I&#39;m moved or ponder about certain things in times like these. It seems to like and respond to different thoughts and observations. It is very pleasant.  
&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Spiritual Moments" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/categories/Spiritual-Moments/"/>
    
    
      <category term="spirituality" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/spirituality/"/>
    
      <category term="moments" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/moments/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Welcome to the Blog</title>
    <link href="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2016/06/15/welcome-post/"/>
    <id>http://adaptivephilosophy.io/2016/06/15/welcome-post/</id>
    <published>2016-06-15T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-12-09T04:30:22.085Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-sec-1&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;Thanks For Visiting My New Website!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&#39;ve been playing around with the blog idea for while, setting it up, and testing different generators and editors. I finally settled on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt; blog with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iissnan/hexo-theme-next&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Next theme&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; for my editor. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nuance.com/for-individuals/by-product/dragon-for-mac/software/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Dragon Dictate&lt;/a&gt; software seems to have difficulty with selecting and editing the text in Emacs, so I also use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Sublime text editor&lt;/a&gt; for dictating text. I write the post in &lt;a href=&quot;http://orgmode.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Org mode&lt;/a&gt;, which the generator renders as HTML when I export it into hexo. So far I am happy with it. I had a little difficulty getting citations to export into HTML correctly, which led me on a small excursion, but I think I can just edit the HTML to have the correct in-text citations for now.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Now for the writing! For this blog, I plan to write about my experiences providing philosophical counseling and helping people with trance/hypnosis/spirituality/meditation over the past few years. I also plan to write about topics that I&#39;m currently researching or reflecting on – usually things related to philosophy, psychology, politics, culture, personal experiences and other interests. I may repost some of my old articles and papers. When I finish reading an article or a book, I may post a short review or some reflections about it. This will be a casual blog with open discussion about anything. If you have any ideas for things you would like to see discussed, please feel free to post the ideas and questions in the comment sections.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The style for the comments is Internet casual conversational; however, please be polite and constructive when discussing topics with others.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Thanks for checking it out. I hope you find something to enjoy. I&#39;ll probably keep tweaking the website for a while, but I hope to have a new post every month or so.  You can check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://adaptivephilosophy.io/about/&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; section for short bio of my adult career and education.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cash.me/$adaptivephilosophy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Much Love! Thank you for your support and encouragement! $&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Blog" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/categories/Blog/"/>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="editors" scheme="http://adaptivephilosophy.io/tags/editors/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
